comminit.com 2009-03-23

# Privacy Policy | The Communication Initiative Network

| 

Average Rating: no ratings submitted

Protecting your privacy is important to us. We strive to keep your personal information confidential. By ensuring that you are aware of and understand our Privacy Policy, we can provide you, a member of our network, with better service. Please take a moment to read the following policy to learn how we handle your personal information.

**Why we collect personal information**

We collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with information relevant to you and your work;
  * To provide you with information relevant to your professional areas of interests;
  * To make a wider range of information available to you;
  * To keep you up to date on the latest news and other information that we think you would like to hear about based on your stated areas of interest and work area.

**How we collect personal information**

We collect information about you in several ways: we ask for your contact information when you correspond with us, register on our website, subscribe to our newsletters, register for our online discussion, and participate in our online surveys. We collect and store the information you provide in a secure database. By providing information through our website when you correspond with us, register on our website, subscribe to our newsletters, register for our online discussions and participate in our online surveys, users should infer that if they provide the Communication Initiative with information we take this as inferred consent.

Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and up to date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used. The information is provided by individuals using our website. It shall be conditional upon the information provided by the individuals. The staff person responsible for overseeing The Communication Initiative Networks collection and use of personal data is the Administrator, Victoria Martin.

The Communication Initiative limits the collection of personal information to that which is necessary for the purposes, identified above, by our organisation.

**When we disclose personal information**

We provide contact information for most every piece of information on our website, so if you are a contact for information on the website, your contact information will be disclosed for networking purposes. You will be alerted to this each and every time it occurs.

We work with our partners (see the list online - [click here](http://www.comminit.com/en/partners.html)) to provide information and support to you, and we may provide your personal information to these partners, within the context of our mission.

At times we may be required by law or legal process to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we believe that disclosure is necessary for the public interest.

Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and up- to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.

Personal information shall not be used or disclosed for the purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the explicit consent of the individual or as required by law.

Individual Access to Information: Upon request, an individual shall be informed of the existence, use, and disclosure of his or her personal information and shall be given access to that information. The individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and MAY have it amended as appropriate after review the organisation, or the Administrator, Victoria Martin.

**How we protect your personal information**

We safeguard the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser.

The Communication Initiative shall make readily available to individuals specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information.

**Collecting other personal information**

When you browse our website, you are able to do so anonymously. Generally, we don’t collect personal information when you browse — not even your email address. Your browser, however, does automatically tell us the type of computer and operating system you are using.

Like many websites, our website uses "cookie" technology. When you first connect to our site, the cookie identifies your browser with a unique, random number. The cookies we use do not reveal any personal information about you, except perhaps your first name so we can welcome you on your next visit. Cookies help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how long they spend there. We use cookies to study traffic patterns on our site so we can make the site even better.

In some of our email communication to you, we use a "click-through URL." When you click one of these URLs, you pass through our web server before arriving at the website that is your destination. We track click-throughs to help us determine your collective interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our network communications.

**Our commitment to privacy**

To make sure your personal information remains confidential, we communicate these privacy guidelines to every employee.

We are anxious to ensure that our privacy policy meets your concerns and responds to your needs. Our Administrator, Victoria Martin is available to receive your enquiries and complaints. You can contact the Administrator at [vmartin@comminit.com](mailto:vmartin@comminit.com), or at The Communication Initiative, 5148 Polson Terrace, Victoria, B.C., Canada, V8Y 2C4, phone number: (250) 658-6372.

We do not knowingly solicit personal information from children or send them requests for personal information.

Our website contains links to other sites. We do not share your personal information with those websites and are not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies.

If we are going to use your personal information differently from that stated at the time of collection, we will try to contact you via email using the most recent information we have. If you have not given us permission to communicate with you, you will not be contacted, nor will we use your personal information in a new manner.

Our Customer Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. We encourage you to review the privacy policy regularly for any changes.

| 

## Help Seed The CI Network

## Development Classifieds

## Evaluating e-Health

**In general, e-Health initiatives are:**
